<?xml version="1.0"?>
<metadata><eainfo><overview xmlns=""><eadetcit>https://www.epa.gov/enviroatlas/enviroatlas-fact-sheets. 

Baynes, J., Neale, A., Hultgren, T. (2022). Improving intelligent dasymetric mapping population density estimates at 30 m resolution for the conterminous United States by excluding uninhabited areas. Earth System Science Data, 14(6), 2833-2849. https://doi.org/10.5194/essd-14-2833-2022</eadetcit><eaover>The US Census Bureau collects population information through the decennial census. Though this information is collected from individual residents, the US Census Bureau aggregates this data into census blocks. Census blocks are statistical areas bounded by both visible features such as roads and streams, as well as invisible boundaries such as county or state limits. This aggregation generally assumes that the population is distributed uniformly across each census block. While this assumption is practical for the purposes of the census, it makes it very difficult to determine how many individuals within a census block live near roads, in floodplains, or face other potential exposures. Traditionally, maps from census data that calculate distance use the centroid of the census block as the starting point. In areas that have large census blocks, this may introduce errors when determining walking or driving distances for individuals. Dasymetric mapping is a geospatial technique that is used to more accurately distribute data assigned to arbitrary boundaries, such as census blocks, using additional information such as land cover types and uses. 

The EnviroAtlas Intelligent Dasymetric Mapping (IDM) toolbox (https://github.com/USEPA/Dasymetric-Toolbox-OpenSource) was used to develop this dataset. The 30 m, Puerto Rico-US Virgin Islands version 2020-6 Land Use land cover classification from the USFS Landscape Change Monitoring System (LCMS) was reclassified to mimic the standard NLCD classification scheme and used as the ancillary raster. 2020 United States Census Blocks with corresponding populations were used as the source units. Some small or irregularly shaped Census Blocks did not align well with the 2020 LCMS raster data meaning that a centroid pixel from the LCMS could not be identified for these blocks. These blocks were absorbed into neighboring census block polygons. The populations of the merged census blocks were added together and then assigned to the pixel level as a single block. 

Numerous additional geospatial datasets relevant to land use (e.g., roads, protected lands, steep slopes, etc.) were used to identify uninhabited areas. LCMS pixels corresponding with areas identified as uninhabited were changed to a new land cover class (i.e., Class Value 0). Additional information about these datasets and the methods used to identify uninhabited areas can be found in the corresponding journal article (Baynes, J., Neale, A., Hultgren, T. (2022). Improving intelligent dasymetric mapping population density estimates at 30 m resolution for the conterminous United States by excluding uninhabited areas. Earth System Science Data, 14(6), 2833-2849. https://doi.org/10.5194/essd-14-2833-2022). Between the development of the 2010 dasymetric allocation of population map and the 2020 version, small deviations from the methods in Baynes et al. 2022 were made. Some of the data used for the 2010 analysis were no longer available, up to date, or had otherwise been changed. ESRI StreetMap Premium North America 2021 version was used instead of the NLCD Impervious Descriptor layer and Navteq LandUse A and B layers to filter out uninhabited areas. ESRI Streets polylines were filtered for function class 1 roads and used to reclassify pixels in the ancillary raster to uninhabited. ESRI StreetMap Premium polygons with FTYPE 1907403, 2000124, 2000200, and 2000420 representing aircraft roads, shopping centers, industrial complexes, and cemeteries respectively were considered uninhabited and masked out.  The parcel data used to identify residential parcels that should be maintained as habitable was switched from CoreLogic to LANDGRID data. Parcels with attribute "lbcs_activity" equal to 1100 (Household) were maintained regardless of overlap with uninhabited area.

In addition to changes in data, a few modifications were made to the methods for the 2020 census analysis. When dissolving small and irregular blocks, a step was added where blocks were first merged with a neighboring block within the same block group where possible, failing that a block within the same tract. Previously uninhabited features within a block were removed if 1) the combined area of mixed-use features covered more that 90% of a block 2) the combined area of all other uninhabited features (buffered aircraft roads, cemeteries, schools, railyards, and parks/forests/wildlife refuges) covered more than 99% of a block. The remaining mixed-use features and uninhabited features were merged into the final uninhabited feature layer. For the 2020 analysis, uninhabited features within a block were removed by 1) combining all mixed-use features and removing any combined feature that covered more that 90% of a block 2) removing any individual uninhabited features in the remaining categories (buffered aircraft roads, cemeteries, schools, railyards, and parks/forests/wildlife refuges) that made up more than 99% of a block 3) combining the retail and other features from steps 1 and 2 and removing any combined feature that covered more than 99% of that block. This modification was done so that an individual feature covering the entire block would not cause all other features for that block group to be removed. 

The IDM toolbox uses three methods to determine representative population densities (RPD) for an ancillary class. Densities can be preset, determined via sampling, or determined via intelligent area weighting (IAW). A class was sampled if at least three source units had greater than 95% of their area covered by that class. IAW was used if a density was not preset or determined via sampling. Representative population densities were determined for 9 land cover classes in Puerto Rico. The new uninhabited class, open water, perennial ice/snow, and emergent wetlands were preset at zero.

For easier readability, the following table can be copied into Excel. The RPDs used for the 2020 dasymetric allocation of population are: State,NLCD Class 0,NLCD Class 11,NLCD Class 12,NLCD Class 23,NLCD Class 42,NLCD Class 81,NLCD Class 82,NLCD Class 90,NLCD Class 95
PR,0,0,0,3.737571989163655,0.0942677033788081,0.0260110119612682,0.3273820647255219,0.0,0

RPDs were used to distribute population to each pixel within each source unit while maintaining the pycnophylactic integrity of the source unit (i.e., the pixel values within each Census Block sum to the population count of that Census Block).</eaover></overview><detailed xmlns=""><enttyp><enttypl>Dasymetric_Population_PR_2020_V1.tif</enttypl><enttypd>Dasymetric population</enttypd><enttypds>US EPA</enttypds></enttyp></detailed></eainfo><mdChar><CharSetCd value="004"/></mdChar><mdHrLv><ScopeCd value="005"/></mdHrLv><mdContact xmlns=""><rpIndName>EnviroAtlas Coordinator</rpIndName><rpOrgName>U.S. Environmental Protection Agency, Office of Research and Development - Center for Public Health and Environmental Assessment (CPHEA), EnviroAtlas</rpOrgName><rpPosName>Geospatial Data Owner</rpPosName><rpCntInfo><cntPhone><voiceNum tddtty="">(919) 541-3832</voiceNum></cntPhone><cntAddress addressType="both"><delPoint>109 T.W. Alexander Drive</delPoint><city>Research Triangle Park</city><adminArea>NC</adminArea><postCode>27709</postCode><eMailAdd>EnviroAtlas@epa.gov</eMailAdd></cntAddress><cntInstr>https://www.epa.gov/enviroatlas</cntInstr></rpCntInfo><role><RoleCd value="007"/></role></mdContact><mdDateSt Sync="FALSE">2022-09-19</mdDateSt><distInfo><distTranOps><onLineSrc><linkage>https://edg.epa.gov/data/PUBLIC/ORD/ENVIROATLAS</linkage><protocol>download</protocol><orFunct><OnFunctCd value="001"/></orFunct></onLineSrc><onLineSrc><linkage>https://enviroatlas.epa.gov/arcgis/rest/services</linkage><protocol>ESRI:ArcGIS</protocol><orFunct><OnFunctCd value="003"/></orFunct></onLineSrc><onLineSrc><linkage>https://www.epa.gov/enviroatlas/enviroatlas-data</linkage><protocol>information</protocol><orFunct><OnFunctCd value="002"/></orFunct></onLineSrc><onLineSrc><linkage>https://www.epa.gov/enviroatlas</linkage><protocol>information</protocol><orFunct><OnFunctCd value="002"/></orFunct></onLineSrc></distTranOps><distFormat><formatName Sync="TRUE">Raster Dataset</formatName></distFormat></distInfo><dataIdInfo><idCitation xmlns=""><resTitle>EnviroAtlas - 2020 Dasymetric Population for Puerto Rico v1</resTitle><citRespParty xmlns=""><rpOrgName>U.S. Environmental Protection Agency (US EPA)</rpOrgName><role><RoleCd value="006"/></role></citRespParty><citRespParty xmlns=""><rpOrgName>U.S. EPA Office of Research and Development (ORD) - Center for Public Health and Environmental Assessment (CPHEA)</rpOrgName><rpCntInfo><cntAddress addressType=""><delPoint>Research Triangle Park, NC</delPoint></cntAddress></rpCntInfo><role><RoleCd value="010"/></role></citRespParty><presForm xmlns=""><PresFormCd value="005" Sync="TRUE"/></presForm><date><pubDate>2022-08-31</pubDate></date></idCitation><idStatus><ProgCd value="001"/></idStatus><idPoC xmlns=""><rpIndName>EnviroAtlas Coordinator</rpIndName><rpOrgName>U.S. Environmental Protection Agency, Office of Research and Development - Center for Public Health and Environmental Assessment (CPHEA), EnviroAtlas</rpOrgName><rpPosName>Geospatial Data Owner</rpPosName><rpCntInfo xmlns=""><cntPhone><voiceNum tddtty="">(919) 541-3832</voiceNum></cntPhone><cntAddress addressType="both"><delPoint>109 T.W. Alexander Drive</delPoint><city>Research Triangle Park</city><adminArea>NC</adminArea><postCode>27709</postCode><eMailAdd>EnviroAtlas@epa.gov</eMailAdd></cntAddress><cntInstr>https://www.epa.gov/enviroatlas</cntInstr></rpCntInfo><role><RoleCd value="010">Publisher</RoleCd></role></idPoC><resMaint xmlns=""><maintFreq><MaintFreqCd value="009"/></maintFreq></resMaint><placeKeys xmlns=""><thesaName xmlns=""><resTitle>EPA Place Names</resTitle><date><pubDate>2015-01-31</pubDate></date><citOnlineRes xmlns=""><linkage>https://ofmpub.epa.gov/sor_internet/registry/termreg/searchandretrieve/taxonomies/search.do?search=&amp;searchString=&amp;taxonomyName=WBT%20-%20Geographic%20Locations</linkage><orFunct><OnFunctCd value="002"/></orFunct><orName>Web Taxonomy - Geographic Locations</orName></citOnlineRes></thesaName><thesaLang><languageCode value="eng"/><countryCode value="US"/></thesaLang><keyword>Puerto Rico</keyword><keyword>United States</keyword></placeKeys><themeKeys xmlns=""><thesaName><resTitle>EPA GIS Keyword Thesaurus</resTitle><date><pubDate>2007-11-02</pubDate></date><citOnlineRes xmlns=""><linkage>https://ofmpub.epa.gov/sor_internet/registry/termreg/searchandretrieve/taxonomies/search.do?search=&amp;searchString=&amp;taxonomyName=WBT%20-%20Geographic%20Locations</linkage><orFunct><OnFunctCd value="002"/></orFunct><orName>EPA Metadata Technical Specification</orName></citOnlineRes></thesaName><thesaLang><languageCode value="eng"/><countryCode value="US"/></thesaLang><keyword>Ecology</keyword><keyword>Ecosystem</keyword><keyword>Environment</keyword><keyword>Human</keyword><keyword>Modeling</keyword></themeKeys><resConst><Consts><useLimit>None. Please check sources, scale, accuracy, currency and other available information. Please confirm that you are using the most recent copy of both data and metadata. Acknowledgement of the EPA would be appreciated.</useLimit></Consts></resConst><dataLang><languageCode value="eng"/><countryCode value="USA" Sync="TRUE"/></dataLang><dataChar><CharSetCd value="004"/></dataChar><resConst><LegConsts><accessConsts><RestrictCd value="009">Unrestricted License</RestrictCd></accessConsts><othConsts>https://edg.epa.gov/EPA_Data_License.html</othConsts><useLimit>EPA Public Domain License</useLimit></LegConsts></resConst><themeKeys xmlns=""><thesaLang><languageCode value="eng"/><countryCode value="US"/></thesaLang><thesaName><resTitle>Federal Program Inventory</resTitle><date><pubDate>2013-09-16</pubDate></date><citOnlineRes xmlns=""><linkage>https://www.performance.gov/federalprograminventory</linkage><orFunct><OnFunctCd value="002"/></orFunct><orName>Federal Program Inventory</orName></citOnlineRes></thesaName><keyword>020:072</keyword></themeKeys><themeKeys xmlns=""><thesaLang><languageCode value="eng"/><countryCode value="US"/></thesaLang><thesaName xmlns=""><resTitle>User</resTitle><date><pubDate>2022-01-03</pubDate></date></thesaName><keyword>Demographics</keyword><keyword>Ecosystem Services</keyword><keyword>EnviroAtlas</keyword><keyword>Environment</keyword><keyword>Environmental Atlas</keyword></themeKeys><idPurp>This dataset is used for metrics that require population to be spatially allocated at a higher resolution than census blocks. This dataset is associated with the journal article (Baynes, J., Neale, A., Hultgren, T. (2022). Improving intelligent dasymetric mapping population density estimates at 30 m resolution for the conterminous United States by excluding uninhabited areas. Earth System Science Data, 14(6), 2833-2849. https://doi.org/10.5194/essd-14-2833-2022).  The overall goal of EnviroAtlas is to employ and develop the best available science to map indicators of ecosystem services production, demand, and drivers for the nation.</idPurp><idAbs>This EnviroAtlas dataset intelligently reallocates 2020 population from census blocks to 30 meter pixels based on land cover and land use. This dataset was produced by the US EPA to support research and online mapping activities related to EnviroAtlas. EnviroAtlas (https://www.epa.gov/enviroatlas) allows the user to interact with a web-based, easy-to-use, mapping application to view and analyze multiple ecosystem services for the contiguous United States. The dataset is available as downloadable data (https://edg.epa.gov/data/Public/ORD/EnviroAtlas) or as an EnviroAtlas map service. Additional descriptive information about this dataset can be found in its associated EnviroAtlas Fact Sheet (https://www.epa.gov/enviroatlas/enviroatlas-fact-sheets).</idAbs><envirDesc Sync="TRUE">Microsoft Windows 10 Version 10.0 (Build 19042) ; Esri ArcGIS 12.8.3.29751</envirDesc><spatRpType><SpatRepTypCd value="002" Sync="TRUE"/></spatRpType><dataExt xmlns=""><geoEle xmlns=""><GeoBndBox esriExtentType="search"><exTypeCode Sync="TRUE">1</exTypeCode><westBL Sync="TRUE">-68.038006</westBL><eastBL Sync="TRUE">-65.136373</eastBL><northBL Sync="TRUE">19.207150</northBL><southBL Sync="TRUE">17.205830</southBL></GeoBndBox></geoEle><tempEle><TempExtent><exTemp><TM_Period xmlns=""><tmBegin>2020-01-01T00:00:00</tmBegin><tmEnd>2020-12-31T00:00:00</tmEnd></TM_Period></exTemp></TempExtent></tempEle></dataExt><idCredit>EPA - EnviroAtlas</idCredit><resConst><SecConsts><class><ClasscationCd value="001">Unclassified</ClasscationCd></class><classSys>https://project-open-data.github.io/schema/#accessLevel</classSys></SecConsts></resConst><tpCat><TopicCatCd value="007"/></tpCat><tpCat><TopicCatCd value="016"/></tpCat></dataIdInfo><mdMaint xmlns=""><maintFreq><MaintFreqCd value="009"/></maintFreq></mdMaint><dqInfo xmlns=""><dqScope><scpLvl><ScopeCd value="005"/></scpLvl></dqScope><report type="DQConcConsis" dimension="" xmlns=""><measDesc>Tests for integrity have not been performed.</measDesc><measResult><ConResult><conSpec><resTitle>EPA National Geospatial Data Policy</resTitle></conSpec><conExpl>Features have been reviewed by U.S. EPA EnviroAtlas Project Managers for public release.</conExpl><conPass>1</conPass></ConResult></measResult></report><report type="DQCompOm" dimension="" xmlns=""><measDesc>Features represented have not been tested for completeness</measDesc><measResult><ConResult><conSpec><resTitle>EPA National Geospatial Data Policy</resTitle></conSpec><conExpl>Features have been reviewed by U.S. EPA EnviroAtlas Project Managers for public release.</conExpl><conPass>1</conPass></ConResult></measResult></report><dataLineage><prcStep xmlns=""><stepDesc>Acquired 2020 US Forest Service Landscape Change Monitoring System (LCMS) Puerto Rico-US Virgin Islands version 2020-6. Reclassified to mimic standard NLCD classification scheme:

Value - Land Cover Classes in LCMS - Reclass Value to Match NLCD

0 - Uninhabited - 0
1 - Agriculture - 82
2 - Developed - 23
3 - Forest - 42
4 - Wetland - 90
5 - Other - 11
6 - Rangeland - 81
7 - Non processing mask - 0
</stepDesc><stepDateTm>2022-01-21T00:00:00</stepDateTm><stepSrc type="used"><srcCitatn><resTitle>2020 US Forest Service Landscape Change Monitoring System Puerto Rico-US Virgin Islands version 2020-6</resTitle><resEd>2020-6</resEd><citOnlineRes><linkage>https://data.fs.usda.gov/geodata/rastergateway/LCMS/index.php</linkage></citOnlineRes></srcCitatn><srcDesc>2020 US Forest Service Landscape Change Monitoring System Puerto Rico-US Virgin Islands version 2020-6</srcDesc></stepSrc></prcStep><prcStep xmlns=""><stepDesc>Acquired National Elevation Dataset (2018; projected to match NLCD) and ESRI StreetMap Premium Streets (ESRI StreetMap Premium, 1.0/2021). Filtered Streets for Function Class 1. LCMS pixels that aligned with rasterized streets or a slope of greater than 25 % were reclassified to an uninhabited land cover class (Class 0). This reclassified raster was the ancillary raster for intelligent dasymetric mapping.</stepDesc><stepDateTm>2022-01-21T00:00:02</stepDateTm><stepSrc type=""><srcDesc>Streets polylines (ESRI StreetMap Premium, 1.0/2021)</srcDesc><srcCitatn><resTitle>ArcGIS StreetMap Premium North America 2021 Release 1</resTitle><resEd>2021</resEd><citOnlineRes><linkage>https://doc.arcgis.com/en/streetmap-premium/get-started/overview.htm</linkage></citOnlineRes></srcCitatn></stepSrc><stepSrc type=""><srcCitatn><resTitle>National Elevation Dataset (NED)</resTitle><citOnlineRes><linkage>https://www.usgs.gov/programs/national-geospatial-program/national-map</linkage></citOnlineRes><otherCitDet>The National Elevation Dataset used in this step was mosaicked together for Alaska in 2021 by EPA EnviroAtlas staff. </otherCitDet></srcCitatn><srcDesc>US Geological Survey (USGS) 30 Meter Resolution, One-Sixtieth Degree National Elevation Dataset for CONUS, Alaska, Hawaii, Puerto Rico, and the U. S. Virgin Islands</srcDesc></stepSrc></prcStep><prcStep xmlns=""><stepDesc>Acquired 2020 US Census Blocks with population counts. Projected blocks to match NLCD. Small or irregularly shaped Census Blocks that would not be represented at a 30 m raster were spatially merged with and had their population added to a neighboring block following the methods in Baynes et al. 2022 with an additional step to merge blocks first within their block group when possible, failing that within their census tract.</stepDesc><stepDateTm>2022-01-24T00:00:01</stepDateTm><stepSrc type="used"><srcCitatn><resTitle>US Census Bureau: US Census Bureau: 2020 TIGER/Line Shapefiles</resTitle><date><pubDate>2021-02-02</pubDate></date><citOnlineRes><linkage>https://www.census.gov/geographies/mapping-files/2020/geo/tiger-line-file.html </linkage></citOnlineRes></srcCitatn></stepSrc></prcStep><prcStep xmlns=""><stepDesc>Acquired MapLandArea polygons (ESRI StreetMap Premium, 1.0/2021), land use (2021) and points of interest (Open Street Maps, 2021), rail lines (North American Rail Network Rail Lines, 2019), residential parcels (LANDGRID, 2021), and protected areas (USGS Protected Areas Database of the U.S. 2.1). All databases were projected to match NLCD. LANDGRID parcels with attribute "lbcs_activity" equal to 1100 (Household) were maintained regardless of overlap with uninhabited features. All other features described were treated as uninhabited features for intelligent dasymetric mapping. Features from these databases were selected and spatially merged following the methods in Baynes et al. 2022. </stepDesc><stepDateTm>2022-08-15T00:00:00</stepDateTm><stepSrc type=""><srcDesc>US Geological Survey, Gap Analysis Program: Protected Areas Database of the United States (PAD-US)</srcDesc><srcCitatn><resTitle>Protected Areas Database of the United States (PAD-US) 2.1</resTitle><date><pubDate>2020-12-23</pubDate></date><resEd>2.1</resEd><citOnlineRes><linkage>https://doi.org/10.5066/P92QM3NT</linkage></citOnlineRes></srcCitatn></stepSrc><stepSrc type=""><srcDesc>2021 Regrid residential parcels</srcDesc><srcCitatn><resTitle>LANDGRID Parcel</resTitle><citOnlineRes><linkage>https://regrid.com/parcels</linkage></citOnlineRes></srcCitatn></stepSrc><stepSrc type=""><srcDesc>Federal Railroad Administration: North American Rail Lines, Bureau of Transportation Statistics, 2019</srcDesc><srcCitatn><resTitle>North American Rail Network Lines</resTitle><date><pubDate>2019-01-01</pubDate></date><citOnlineRes><linkage>https://data-usdot.opendata.arcgis.com/datasets/usdot::north-american-rail-network-lines/explore?location=35.731057%2C-108.308501%2C3.79</linkage></citOnlineRes></srcCitatn></stepSrc><stepSrc type=""><srcDesc>MapLandArea polygons (ESRI StreetMap Premium, 1.0/2021)</srcDesc><srcCitatn><resTitle>ArcGIS StreetMap Premium North America 2021 Release 1</resTitle><citOnlineRes><linkage>https://doc.arcgis.com/en/streetmap-premium/get-started/overview.htm</linkage></citOnlineRes></srcCitatn></stepSrc><stepSrc type=""><srcDesc>Land use 2021 and Places of interest 2021 from OpenStreetMap contributors: Planet dump, Planet OSM. </srcDesc><srcCitatn><resTitle>Land use 2021; Places of interest 2021</resTitle><citOnlineRes><linkage>https://planet.osm.org</linkage></citOnlineRes></srcCitatn></stepSrc></prcStep><prcStep xmlns=""><stepDesc>Used the EnviroAtlas Dasymetric Toolbox for Open Source GIS (https://github.com/USEPA/Dasymetric-Toolbox-OpenSource) to estimate population density. Uninhabited Class (0), Water (11), Perennial Ice/Snow (12), and Emergent Wetlands (95) were given preset representative population densities of 0.</stepDesc><stepDateTm>2022-08-16T00:00:00</stepDateTm></prcStep></dataLineage></dqInfo><Esri><scaleRange><minScale>150000000</minScale><maxScale>50000</maxScale></scaleRange><DataProperties><itemProps><imsContentType export="False"/><itemName Sync="TRUE">PR_Dasy.tif</itemName><itemLocation><linkage Sync="TRUE">file://C:\Users\akillea\Desktop\Dasy_v2\PR_Dasy.tif</linkage><protocol Sync="TRUE">Local Area Network</protocol></itemLocation><nativeExtBox><westBL Sync="TRUE">3034184.967393</westBL><eastBL Sync="TRUE">3327404.967393</eastBL><southBL Sync="TRUE">-83895.363657</southBL><northBL Sync="TRUE">46184.636343</northBL><exTypeCode Sync="TRUE">1</exTypeCode></nativeExtBox></itemProps><coordRef><type Sync="TRUE">Projected</type><geogcsn Sync="TRUE">GCS_North_American_1983</geogcsn><csUnits Sync="TRUE">Linear Unit: Meter (1.000000)</csUnits><projcsn Sync="TRUE">USA_Contiguous_Albers_Equal_Area_Conic_USGS_version</projcsn><peXml Sync="TRUE">&lt;ProjectedCoordinateSystem xsi:type='typens:ProjectedCoordinateSystem' xmlns:xsi='http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance' xmlns:xs='http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema' xmlns:typens='http://www.esri.com/schemas/ArcGIS/2.8.0'&gt;&lt;WKT&gt;PROJCS[&amp;quot;USA_Contiguous_Albers_Equal_Area_Conic_USGS_version&amp;quot;,GEOGCS[&amp;quot;GCS_North_American_1983&amp;quot;,DATUM[&amp;quot;D_North_American_1983&amp;quot;,SPHEROID[&amp;quot;GRS_1980&amp;quot;,6378137.0,298.257222101]],PRIMEM[&amp;quot;Greenwich&amp;quot;,0.0],UNIT[&amp;quot;Degree&amp;quot;,0.0174532925199433]],PROJECTION[&amp;quot;Albers&amp;quot;],PARAMETER[&amp;quot;False_Easting&amp;quot;,0.0],PARAMETER[&amp;quot;False_Northing&amp;quot;,0.0],PARAMETER[&amp;quot;Central_Meridian&amp;quot;,-96.0],PARAMETER[&amp;quot;Standard_Parallel_1&amp;quot;,29.5],PARAMETER[&amp;quot;Standard_Parallel_2&amp;quot;,45.5],PARAMETER[&amp;quot;Latitude_Of_Origin&amp;quot;,23.0],UNIT[&amp;quot;Meter&amp;quot;,1.0],AUTHORITY[&amp;quot;Esri&amp;quot;,102039]]&lt;/WKT&gt;&lt;XOrigin&gt;-16901100&lt;/XOrigin&gt;&lt;YOrigin&gt;-6972200&lt;/YOrigin&gt;&lt;XYScale&gt;266467840.99085236&lt;/XYScale&gt;&lt;ZOrigin&gt;-100000&lt;/ZOrigin&gt;&lt;ZScale&gt;10000&lt;/ZScale&gt;&lt;MOrigin&gt;-100000&lt;/MOrigin&gt;&lt;MScale&gt;10000&lt;/MScale&gt;&lt;XYTolerance&gt;0.001&lt;/XYTolerance&gt;&lt;ZTolerance&gt;0.001&lt;/ZTolerance&gt;&lt;MTolerance&gt;0.001&lt;/MTolerance&gt;&lt;HighPrecision&gt;true&lt;/HighPrecision&gt;&lt;WKID&gt;102039&lt;/WKID&gt;&lt;LatestWKID&gt;102039&lt;/LatestWKID&gt;&lt;/ProjectedCoordinateSystem&gt;</peXml></coordRef><RasterProperties><General><PixelDepth Sync="TRUE">32</PixelDepth><HasColormap Sync="TRUE">FALSE</HasColormap><CompressionType Sync="TRUE">LZW</CompressionType><NumBands Sync="TRUE">1</NumBands><Format Sync="TRUE">TIFF</Format><HasPyramids Sync="TRUE">TRUE</HasPyramids><SourceType Sync="TRUE">continuous</SourceType><PixelType Sync="TRUE">floating point</PixelType><NoDataValue Sync="TRUE">-999</NoDataValue></General></RasterProperties><lineage><Process ToolSource="c:\program files\arcgis\pro\Resources\ArcToolbox\toolboxes\Data Management Tools.tbx\CopyRaster" Date="20220826" Time="105100" Name="" export="">CopyRaster AK_Dasy.tif C:\Users\akillea\Desktop\Dasy_v2\Done_AK_Dasy.tif # # -999 NONE NONE "32 bit float" NONE NONE "TIFF format" NONE CURRENT_SLICE NO_TRANSPOSE</Process><Process ToolSource="c:\program files\arcgis\pro\Resources\ArcToolbox\toolboxes\Data Management Tools.tbx\CopyRaster" Date="20220829" Time="072830" Name="" export="">CopyRaster Done_PR_Dasy.tif C:\Users\akillea\Desktop\Dasy_v2\PR_Dasy.tif # # -999 NONE NONE "32 bit float" NONE NONE "TIFF format" NONE CURRENT_SLICE NO_TRANSPOSE</Process><Process ToolSource="c:\program files\arcgis\pro\Resources\ArcToolbox\Toolboxes\Data Management Tools.tbx\Rename" Date="20220901" Time="093825" Name="" export="">Rename C:\Users\akillea\Desktop\Dasy_v2\PR_Dasy.tif C:\Users\akillea\Desktop\Dasy_v2\2020_Dasymetric_Population_PUERTO_RICO_V1.tif RasterDataset</Process></lineage></DataProperties><ArcGISFormat>1.0</ArcGISFormat><ArcGISProfile>ISO19115_3</ArcGISProfile><SyncDate>20220829</SyncDate><SyncTime>07283000</SyncTime><ModDate>20220919</ModDate><ModTime>10403700</ModTime><CreaDate>20220810</CreaDate><CreaTime>14161600</CreaTime><SyncOnce>FALSE</SyncOnce></Esri><mdLang><languageCode value="eng"/><countryCode value="USA" Sync="TRUE"/></mdLang><mdHrLvName Sync="TRUE">dataset</mdHrLvName><refSysInfo><RefSystem dimension=""><refSysID><identCode code="102039" Sync="TRUE"/><idCodeSpace Sync="TRUE">Esri</idCodeSpace><idVersion Sync="TRUE">8.1.2</idVersion></refSysID></RefSystem></refSysInfo><spatRepInfo><Georect><cellGeo><CellGeoCd Sync="TRUE" value="002"/></cellGeo><numDims Sync="TRUE">2</numDims><tranParaAv Sync="TRUE">1</tranParaAv><chkPtAv Sync="TRUE">0</chkPtAv><cornerPts><pos Sync="TRUE">3034184.967393 -83895.363657</pos></cornerPts><cornerPts><pos Sync="TRUE">3034184.967393 46184.636343</pos></cornerPts><cornerPts><pos Sync="TRUE">3327404.967393 46184.636343</pos></cornerPts><cornerPts><pos Sync="TRUE">3327404.967393 -83895.363657</pos></cornerPts><centerPt><pos Sync="TRUE">3180794.967393 -18855.363657</pos></centerPt><axisDimension type="002"><dimSize Sync="TRUE">9774</dimSize><dimResol><value Sync="TRUE" uom="m">30.000000</value></dimResol></axisDimension><axisDimension type="001"><dimSize Sync="TRUE">4336</dimSize><dimResol><value Sync="TRUE" uom="m">30.000000</value></dimResol></axisDimension><ptInPixel><PixOrientCd Sync="TRUE" value="001"/></ptInPixel></Georect></spatRepInfo><contInfo><ImgDesc xmlns=""><contentTyp><ContentTypCd Sync="TRUE" value="001"/></contentTyp><covDim><Band xmlns=""><dimDescrp Sync="TRUE">Band_1</dimDescrp><maxVal Sync="TRUE">144.250000</maxVal><minVal Sync="TRUE">0.000000</minVal><bitsPerVal Sync="TRUE">32</bitsPerVal><valUnit><UOM type="length" gmlID=""><unitSymbol>[arb'U]</unitSymbol></UOM></valUnit><seqID><aName>1</aName><attributeType><aName>1</aName></attributeType></seqID></Band></covDim><attDesc>Number of people allocated to the pixel</attDesc><trianInd>False</trianInd><radCalDatAv>False</radCalDatAv><camCalInAv>False</camCalInAv><filmDistInAv>False</filmDistInAv><lensDistInAv>False</lensDistInAv></ImgDesc></contInfo><mdFileID>D7A556CC-A619-411A-81F0-072D328A7F21</mdFileID></metadata>
